A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- SIX SONATES EN TRIO Deux Violons et Basse continuë DEDIEES A Son Altesse MONSEIGNEUR LE PRINCE CHARLES DE LA TOUR TASSIS. PAR HENRY IAQUES DE CROES. ŒUVRE IIIE. Prix 9tt. A PARIS, Chez Me. Boivin, Mde. Rüe St. Honoré, a la Regle d'Or. Mr. Le Clerc, Md. Rue du Roule, a la Croix d'Or., 1751 or 1752; C4502 ("Six Sonates en trio pour les violons"; Sonata V: A major); Three parts, quarto, 278x206 (283x212): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-24. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-19. Blank, [20]. Basso: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18].
  Da Capella C|
  Affettuoso 3
  Tempo di Menuetto 3/8
  Largetto 3/8
  Gratioso 3/8
  Allo 3
  Cicilliana Largo 6/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Croes, Hendrik-Jacques de; Boivin, Mme. (Elisabeth-Catherine Ballard), d. 1776; Le Clerc, Jean-Pantaléon, d. 1759; Règle d'Or; Paris (France); Fugue; Minuet; Siciliana; A; B♭; D; G; 2/4; 3; 3/2; 3/8; 6/8; C; C|; Adagio; Affettuoso; Allegro; Andante; Cicilliana largo; Da cappella; Fuga allegro; Grazioso; Grave; Larghetto; Tempo di menuetto
  Appears in Le Clerc's catalogue of 1752.
  Devriès-Lesure no. 121. See also Devriès, p. 172.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- SIX SONATES EN TRIO POUR LES VIOLONS FLUTES TE BASSE CONTINUE PAR HENRY JACQUES DE CROES ŒURE VE. Gravées par Melle. Michelon. Prix 6tt SE VEND A PARIS Chez Mr. Le Clerc Md. Rue du Roule à la Croix d'Or. Mme. Boivin Mde. Rue St. Honoré à la Régle d'Or. AVEC PRIVILÉGE DU ROY., Between 1762 and 1768; C4503 ("flûtes"); Three parts, quarto, 258x194 (265x201): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-12. Blank, [13]. Music, pp. 14-16. Blank, [17]. Music, pp. 18-20. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-5. Blank, [6]. Music, pp. 7-12. Blank, [13]. Music, pp. 14-16. Blank, [17]. Music, pp. 18-19. Blank, [20]. Basso: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-5. Blank, [6]. Music, pp. 7-16. All three title-pages signed: "Bateman 1746".
  Affectuoso e Gratioso 3/8
  Tempo di minuetto 3/8
  Arioso Andante 3/8
  Tempo di menuetto 3
  Andante e cantabile 2/4
  SONATA VI d
  Fuga allegro C
  Grave 2/4
  Allegro 3
  Trio sonatas, op. 5; Croes, Hendrik-Jacques de; Boivin, Mme. (Elisabeth-Catherine Ballard), d. 1776; Croix d'Or; Le Clerc, Jean-Pantaléon, d. 1759; Règle d'Or; Michelon, Mlle.; Paris (France); Arioso; Fugue; Minuet; F; G; A; D; 2; 2/4; 3; 3/8; C; Adagio; Affectuoso e grazioso; Allegro; Allegro ma non presto; Andante e cantabile; Arioso andante; Fuga allegro; Grave; Larghetto; Largo; Tempo di menuetto; Tempo di minuetto
  Le Clerc lists the composer's op. 4 in his catalogue of 1762 (Devriès-Lesure no. 132) and op. 6 in his catalogue of 1768 (no. 133).
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- Trois QUATUORS CONCERTANS Pour Flûte, Violon, Alto, et Basse. PAR DEVIENNE 3e. Livre de Quatuors. Prix 9tt. A PARIS Chez Augte. LEDUC, Editeur et Md. de Musique, Rue de la Loi, No 78, près celle Feydeau. Propriété de l'Editeur, Ecrit par Ribiere. 292, 1797; Deest.; Four parts, quarto, 262x183 (264x197): Flute: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. Violino: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-10. Alto: Same as Flute. Basso: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-7. Blank, [8]. Unfigured. Plate no. 292 throughout. Bound with nos. 189, 211, 212, and 216.
  Ir. QUATUOR G
  Allegro poco Mod. C
  Grazioso Con Variat. 2/4
  QUATUOR II F
  Allo. vivace 3/4
  Rondeau Allto. Poco Moderato 6/8
  QUATUOR III g
  Allo. Affectoso C
  Quatuors concertants, flute, strings, 3e livre; Devienne, François, 1759-1803; Leduc, Auguste (Antoine-Pierre-Auguste), 1779-1823; Ribiere; Leduc, Auguste (Antoine-Pierre-Auguste), 1779-1823; Paris (France); Rondo; Variations; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C; Allegro poco moderato; Allegretto affettuoso; Allegretto vivace; Grazioso con variazioni; Presto; Rondeau allegretto poco moderato
  Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 102.
  Affiches, annonces et avis divers
  , Supplement of January 22, 1797.
  - Flute
  - Violino
  - Alto
  - Basso
- SIX TRIOS A Deux Violons et Basse Composés PAR Mr. Dolphin Œuvre. 1e. A PARIS Chez Le Sr Sieber, musicien rue St Honoré à l'hôtel D'aligre Ancien Grand Conseil. Et aux adresses Ordinaires A LYON M. Casteau A. BRUXCELLES M. Godfroy A BORDEAU M. Seaunier Gravé par Md. Sieber. Prix. 7tt. 4s. A P D R, 1774; D3357; Three parts, folio, 253x189 (273x197): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino Secondo: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. Unfigured. Title-page of Violino Primo signed in lower right: "Sieber".
  Rondeau molto Gratioso 2
  TRIO II F
  Rondeau Gratioso 6/8
  TRIO III B♭
  Allo. Commodo C
  Rondeau 2/4
  TRIO IV E♭
  Andante 3
  TRIO VI D
  Rondeau Allegrino 2/4
  Trios, violins, violoncello, op. 1; Dolphin; Casteau; Godfroy, M.; Seaunier, M.; Sieber, Jean-George, 1738-1822; Sieber, Marie Julie Regnaud; Paris (France); Brussels (Belgium); Lyon (France); Bordeaux (Aquitaine, France); Rondo; B♭; C; D; E♭; F; 2; 2/4; 3; 6/8; Allegro; Allegretto comodo; Andante; Rondeau; Rondeau allegrino; Rondeau grazioso; Rondeau molto grazioso
  Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 142.
  , November 28, 1774.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- XII SONATINE NOTTURNE per due Flauti Traverssi ò due Violini Composti per Sua Maestà Rè di Prusia dal Dottel Figlio LONDON Printed for J. Oswald at his Musick Shop in St. Martin's Church Yard, of whom may be had [list of works beginning with: "The comic Tunes & Songs in Queen Mab" and ending with "The May Pole 2 Books, each"] With great variety of the newest Musick vocal & Instrumental., ca. 1753; D3467; Score, folio, 252x180 (267x184): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-12.
  Notturno I D
  Allegro sostenuto 2/4
  Notturno II D
  Allo. Gratioso 3/8
  Notturno III G
  Notturno IV G
  Notturno V D
  Notturno VI D
  Notturno VII G
  Notturno VIII G
  Notturno IX C
  Notturno X C
  Notturno XI G
  Notturno XII G
  Allo. Caccia 6/8
  Sonatine notturne, flutes (2); Dôthel, Niccolò, 1721-1810; Hallet, Benjamin; Oswald, James, 1710-1769; Oswald, James, 1710-1769; Oswald, James, 1710-1769; London (England); Caccia; C; D; G; 2/4; 3/8; 6/8; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro moderato; Allegro sostenuto; Allegro caccia; Allegro grazioso; Grazioso
  See Frank Kidson, "James Oswald, Dr. Burney, and `The Temple of Apollo'," The Musical Antiquary, 2 ( 1910 ), pp. 39-40.
  "Dottel Figlio" and "Nicolas Dothel" were probably pseudonyms for James Oswald or Benjamin Hallet.
- Six SONATAS in Three Parts FOR A GERMAN FLUTE, A VIOLIN, with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD or VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. NICOLAS DÔTHEL LE FILS. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had For 2 German Flutes and a Bass. [list of works beginning with: "Kleinknecht's Sonatas" and ending with: "Tessarinis 12 Solos"], 1761; D3452; Three parts, quarto, 250x183 (264x190): FLAUTO TRAVERSA: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO: Same as FLAUTO TRAVERSA. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10].
  SONATA III e
  Allegro Fuga C
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Dôthel, Niccolò, 1721-1810; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Fugue; A; D; G; E; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro fuga; Allegro moderato; Andante; Presto
  Smith-Humphries, no. 586.
  , July 14, 1761.
  See Notes to no. 103.
  - FLAUTO TRAVERSA
  - VIOLINO
  - BASSO
- Je suis un Pauvre Miserable Ariette ajustée a deux Violons ou deux flutes avec des Variations Prix 12s. Par lauteur du Coeur Volage avec Variations et des bagatelles Varieés Aparis Chez dufour Libraire quay de Gesvres a lange gardiens et aux adresses Ordinaires de Musique, Between 1760 (composition of the opera) and 1794 (introduction of francs and centimes); DD3758a; Score, quarto, 268x204 (272x205): Blank, [1]. Music, pp. [2-3]. Blank, [4].
  Isle des foux. Je suis un pauvre misérable; arr.; Duni, Egidio, 1708-1775; Dufour
  Title taken from first page of music.
- SIX SONATES POUR Le Violoncelle OU Violon et Basse DÉDIÉES A Son Altesse Sérénissime Monseigneur LE PRINCE DE CONTY COMPOSÉES PAR MR DUPORT De la Musique de son Altesse. Mis au jour par MR. DE LA CHEVARDIERE. Gravé par Madme. Oger. Prix 7tt. 4s. A PARIS Chez Mr. De la Chevardiere Md. de Musique du Roi, ruë du Roule à la Croix d'Or, Et aux adresses ordinaires de Musique. AVEC PRIVILEGE DU ROI., 1775; D3874; Score, quarto, 248x181 (257x186): Title, verso catalogue [Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 81, No. I, with heading trimmed]. Catalogue, [Johansson/ French, facs. 59], [1]. Music, pp. 2-25. Blank, [26].
  Non tanto Allegro 3
  Rondeau C|
  Menuet 3
  Sonatas, violoncello, continuo, op. 1 (Chevardiere); Duport, Jean-Pierre, 1741-1818; La Chevardière, Louis Balthazard de, 1730-1812; Croix d'Or; Oger, Madame; La Chevardière, Louis Balthazard de, 1730-1812; Paris (France); Minuet; Rondo; A; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Andante; Menuet; Minuetto; Non tanto allegro; Rondeau; Tempo di minuetto
  Issued with two catalogues of the same date. Originally published in 1766. Announced as op. 1 in one of the publisher's catalogues of 1766 (Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 71).
- Six DUETTOS for a Violin and TENOR Composed by Ernesto Eichner Op. X. Price 7sh. 6d. London Printed by Longman and Broderip No: 26 CHEAPSIDE., ca. 1780; E561; Two parts, folio, 274x169 (289x208): VIOLINO: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. VIOLA: Same as VIOLINo.
  Allegro Moderato C|
  Rondò Andantino 6/8
  DUETTO II D
  Rondò Allegro 2/4
  Allegro Molto 2/4
  Rondò 2/4
  DUETTO IV c
  Allo= Moderato C|
  Andante Moderato 3/4
  Allegretto Moderato 2/4
  Allo= Moderato 3/4
  Rond'o Andante 2/4
  DUETTO VI F
  Allo= Maestoso C
  Rondò Moderato 2/4
  Sonatas, violin, viola, op. 10; Eichner, Ernst, 1740-1777; Longman and Broderip [London, England]; London (England); Rondo; A; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Allegretto moderato; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro molto; Allegro maestoso; Andante moderato; Rondo andante; Rondò; Rondò allegro; Rondò andantino; Rondò moderato
  At end of music on p. 14 of VIOLINO: "Grave par I. G. Fambach". Marianne Reissinger ("Eichner, Ernst," The New Grove, v. 6, p. 81) considers these works to be spurious. Bound with nos. 30, 40, 181, and 210.
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLA
- DUO POUR DEUX VIOLONS Par le Sr: CHARLES FERRARI Ordinaire de la Musique De L'Infant Don Philippe Prix [obliterated] tt. A PARIS Chez Mr. de la Chevardiere rue du Roule à la Croix d'or, Marchand de Musique du Roi et de la Famille Royalle AVEC PRIVILEGE DU ROI. Gravé par Melle. Vendôme, 1768?; F272; Score, folio, 300x210 (306x217): Title, verso blank. Catalogue, [Johansson/French, v. 2, pp. 73-74], [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18].
  DUO I A
  Cantabille C|
  II DUO D
  Ande: Assai 2/4
  Allo: 3/8
  III DUO G
  Adao: C|
  IV DUO D
  Alleo: nontanto 2/4
  Ande. 3/4
  V DUO A
  Ado. C|
  TRIO a Violino e Violoncello e Basso G
  Presto 3/4. Figured.
  Duets, violins, op. 4; Trio, violin, violoncello, bass, G major; Ferrari, Carlo, 1714-1790; La Chevardière, Louis Balthazard de, 1730-1812; Croix d'Or; Vendôme, Marie-Charlotte; Paris (France); A; D; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro non tanto; Allegretto; Andante; Andante assai; Cantabille; Presto; Spiritoso
  Issued with catalogue of the same date. Originally published in 1764 or 1765, appearing in Chevardiere's catalogue of 1765 (Johansson/French, facs. 50) but not of 1764 (Johansson/French, v. 1, p. 68).
  Chevardiere's price for this item throughout his catalogues is 6 livres (see Johansson/French). At bottom of page 12 (first page of TRIO...): "Gravé par Me.lle Vendôme".
- Six SONATAS for a Violin and a Bass Dedicated To His Excellency The PRINCE DON LORENZO CORSINI Great Chamberlain to his Imperial MAJESTY &c. &c. &c. BY DOMENICO FERRARI. LONDON Printed for John Cox at Simpson's Musick Shop in Sweetings Alley, opposite the East Door of the Royal Exchange, of whom may be had, For the Harpsicord Violin or Bass, [list of works beginning with: "Degiardino's Solos Duets and Sonatas." and ending with: "Groneman's ditto.", Between 1757 and 1764; Deest.; Score, folio, 263x188 (271x198): Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-37. Blank, [38].
  Andante 12/8
  Rondo 3/4
  Cantabile 2/4
  Adagio è Cantabile C
  Adagio, è Cantabile C
  Allo. Grao. 2/4
  Minuetto con Variazioni 3/4
  Sonatas, violin, continuo, op. 1; Ferrari, Domenico, 1722-1780; Simpson's Musick Shop; Cox, John; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; Variations; A; B♭; C; D; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; C|; Adagio; Adagio è cantabile; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro grazioso; Andante; Andantino; Cantabile; Largo; Minuetto; Minuetto con variazioni; Rondo
  The set was originally published in Paris ca. 1757 (see
  Virginia Downman Kock, "The Works of Domenico Ferrari," Ph.D. diss., Tulane, 1969
  , pp. 44-45.); Cox was at this address until 1764.
- EIGHT CONCERTO'S IN SEVEN PARTS, COMPOS'D By MICHAEL CHRISTIAN FESTING. OPERA QUINTA. LONDON: Printed by WILLIAM SMITH, at Corelli's Head, near St. Clement's Church in the Strand; and Sold only by the Author, at his House in Angel-Court, in Windmill-Street, near the Upper-end of the Hay-Market. (Price one Guinea.) Where may be had, OPERA PRIMA, being Twelve SOLO'S for a Violin, &c. Price one Guinea. OPERA SECUNDA, being Twelve SONATA'S in three Parts. Price one Guinea. OPERA TERZA, being twelve CONCERTO'S in seven Parts. Price one Guinea and a Half. OPERA QUARTA, being Eight SOLO'S for a Violin, &c. Price Half a Guinea. M.DCC.XXXIX., 1739. Title-page; F675; Seven parts, folio, 253x185: VIOLINO PRIMO DEL CONCERTINO: Title, verso Royal Privilege, dated "the 22d Day of January 1729-30" and signed "Holles Newcastle". "A LIST OF THE SUBSCRIBERS.", pp. [i-iii]. Blank, [iv]. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-12. Blank, [13]. Music, pp. 14-22. VIOLINO SECONDO DEL CONCERTINO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18]. VIOLINO PRIMO RIPIENO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. VIOLINO SECONDO RIPIENO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-12. VIOLA: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO RIPIENO. VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-15. Blank, [16]. Figured bass. ORGANO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-11. Blank, [12].
  Andante è Spiritoso C
  Allegro Assai 2/4
  Allegro Assai 3/4
  CONCERTO III c
  CONCERTO IV B♭
  Largo 6/8
  CONCERTO VI E♭
  CONCERTO VII G
  Spiritoso C - Allegro C
  CONCERTO VIII C
  Concertos in 7 parts, op. 5; Festing, Michael Christian, d. 1752; Smith, William, fl. 1720-1763; London (England); A; B♭; C; E♭; G; D; 2/4; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Andante è spiritoso; Grave; Largo; Poco allegro; Presto; Spiritoso
  Title page, Royal Privilege, and List of the Subscribers are in letterpress; the music is engraved.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO DEL CONCERTINO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO DEL CONCERTINO
  - VIOLINO PRIMO RIPIENO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO RIPIENO
  - VIOLA
  - VIOLONCELLO
  - ORGANO
- TWELVE SOLO'S FOR A Violin and Thorough Bass. Dedicated to the RIGHT HONOURABLE OTHER WINDSOR, EARL of Plymouth, BARON WINDSOR of Bradenham, &c. &c. COMPOS'D By MICHAEL CHRISTIAN FESTING. OPERA PRIMA. LONDON: Printed by WILLIAM SMITH at Correlli's Head near St. Clement's Church in the Strand; and sold only by the author, at his House in Kemp-Court in Berwick-Street near Golden-Square. MDCCXXX. Price One Guinea., 1730. Title-page; F665; Score, quarto, 276x204: Title-page, verso Royal Privilege dated "the 22d Day of January 1729-30" and signed "Holles Newcastle". Dedication, verso blank, [i-ii]. "A LIST OF THE SUBSCRIBERS.", pp. [iii-vi]. Music, pp. 1-55. Blank, [56].
  Sonata I E
  Sonata II c
  Sonata III A
  Sonata IV E♭
  Allegro ma non troppo 12/8
  Sonata VII B♭
  Sonata IX G
  Sonata X D
  Cannone Largo C
  Sonata XI f
  Sonata XII E♭
  Aria Allegro C
  Solos, violin, continuo, op. 1; Festing, Michael Christian, d. 1752; Smith, William, fl. 1720-1763; London (England); Aria; Canon; Gavotte; Jig; Minuet; A; B♭; D; E; E♭; G; C; F; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro ma non troppo; Aria allegro; Canone largo; Gavotta allegro; Giga allegro; Grave; Largo; Minuet; [no indication]
  Title-page, Royal Privilege, and List of Subscribers are in letterpress; the music is engraved. List of Subscribers has some additions in MS.
- SIX SOLOS for a VIOLIN with a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICHORD Composed by Michael Christian Festing Opera ottava. LONDON Printed for J. Johnson at the Harp and Crown in Cheapside, Where may be had composed by the same Author. [list of works beginning with: "J2 Solos for a Violin Op. Jst." and ending with: "6 Duets for Violins or German Flutes."], ca. 1750; F681; Score, folio, 244x182 (262x190): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-28.
  Andantino è Dolce 2/4
  Menuetto Gratiosamente 3/4
  Andante Spiritoso C
  Allegro [C]
  Aria, Amoroso 3/8
  Poco Allegro Gratioso 2/4
  Allegro Spiritoso 6/8
  Andante Amoroso 3/4
  Allegro Assai 12/8
  Aria, Moderato 3/8
  Solos, violin, continuo, op. 8; Festing, Michael Christian, d. 1752; Harp and Crown; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Aria; Minuet; A; D; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro spiritoso; Allegro moderato; Andante; Andante amoroso; Andante spiritoso; Andantino è dolce; Aria amoroso; Aria moderato; Grave; Largo; Menuetto graziosamente; Poco allegro; Poco allegro grazioso; Spiritoso
- TWELVE SONATA'S, In Three PARTS; Dedicated to HER GRACE, HENRIETTA, Dutchess of Marlborough, &c. &c. The First, Second, and Third Sonata's, for two German Flutes, [or two Violins] and a Bass. The Fourth, Fifth, and Sixth Sonata's, for one German Flute, one Violin, [or two Violins] and a Bass. The Seventh, Eighth, Ninth, Tenth, Eleventh, and Twelfth Sonata's, for two Violins and a Bass. Compos'd by MICHAEL CHRISTIAN FESTING. OPERA SECUNDA. LONDON: Printed by WILLIAM SMITH, at CORRELLI'S Head, near St. Clement's Church in the Strand; and Sold only by the Author, at his House in Angel Court in Windmill-street, near the upper End of the Hay-Market. (Price One Guinea.) Where may also be had, (and no where else) Twelve SOLO'S for a Violin And Thorough Bass, compos'd by the same Author. Price One Guinea. M.DCC.XXXI., 1731. Title-page; F668.; Three parts, folio, 265x190: First GERMAN FLUTE or VIOLIN: Title, verso Royal Privilege dated "the 22d Day of January 1729-30" and signed "Holles Newcastle". Letter of dedication, verso blank, pp. [i-ii]. "A LIST OF THE SUBSCRIBERS.", pp. [iii- vi]. Music, pp. 1-21. Blank, [22]. Heading on pp. 7-11 (SonatasIV-VI): "GERMAN FLUTE or First VIOLIN". Heading on pp. 12-21: "First Violin". Second GERMAN FLUTE or VIOLIN: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-18. Heading on pp. 5-9 (Sonatas IV-VI):"VIOLIN". Heading on pp. 10-18: "Second VIOLIN". BASS: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-18.
  Sonata I b
  Largo e Piano 3/4
  Sonata III G
  Sonata IV e
  Sonata V g
  Sonata VI D
  Sonata VII e
  Sonata VIII A
  Sonata IX B♭
  Largo è Staccato C
  Allegro assai 12/8
  Sonata X c
  Allegro e Spiritoso 3/8
  Allegro e Staccato C
  Allegro è Staccato 6/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 2; Festing, Michael Christian, d. 1752; Smith, William, fl. 1720-1763; London (England); Minuet; A; B♭; D; E♭; G; B; C; E; 12/8; 2/4; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro e spiritoso; Allegro e staccato; Allegro ma non troppo; Allegro è staccato; Andante; Grave; Largo; Largo e piano; Largo è staccato; Minuet; Minuet andante; Presto; Tempo giusto
  Title-page, Royal Privilege, and List of Subscribers are in letterpress; the music is engraved. One MS addition to the List of Subscribers: "Mr. Tom Hayes Organist of St. Marys Shrewsbury".
  - First GERMAN FLUTE or VIOLIN
  - Second GERMAN FLUTE or VIOLIN
  - BASS
- SIX SONATA'S FOR TWO VIOLINS and a BASS. Dedicated to WILLIAM TRUMBULL Esq; COMPOS'D By MICHAEL CHRISTIAN FESTING. OPERA SESTA. LONDON: Printed by WILLIAM SMITH, in Middle-Row, Holbourn; and Sold only by thje Author, at his House in Queen-Street, near Golden Square. (Price Half a Guinea.) Where may be had, Compos'd by the same Author, OPERA PRIMA, being Twelve SOLO'S for a Violin, &c. Price one Guinea. OPERA SECUNDA, being Twelve SONATA'S in three Parts. Price one Guinea. OPERA TERZA, being twelve CONCERTO'S in seven Parts. Price one Guinea and a Half. OPERA QUARTA, being Eight SOLO'S for a Violin, OPERA QUINTA, being Eight CONCERTO's in seven Parts. Price one Guinea." M.DCC.XXXXII., 1742. Title-page; F677 (SONATA VI: G major); Three parts, folio, 253x185: VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso Royal Privilege dated "the 22d Day of January 1729-30" and signed "Holles Newcastle". "A LIST OF THE SUBSCRIBERS.", pp. [i-iv], with brackets around pagination in the original. Letter of dedication, p. [ VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Title, verso Royal Privilege. Music, pp. 1-12.
  Allegro ma non troppo 3/4
  Allemanda Non troppo Allegro C
  Poco Allegro e Dolce C
  Andante e Dolce 3/4
  Marcia Largo e Piano C
  Poco Allegro C
  Largo e Dolce 3/4
  Largo Affettuoso C
  Trio sonatas, op. 6; Festing, Michael Christian, d. 1752; Smith, William, fl. 1720-1763; London (England); Allemande; March; B♭; C; E♭; D; E; G; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro ma non troppo; Allemanda non troppo allegro; Andante; Andante grazioso; Andante e dolce; Larghetto; Largo; Largo affettuoso; Largo e dolce; Marcia largo e piano; Poco allegro; Poco allegro e dolce; Presto
  Title-page, Royal Privilege, List of Subscribers, and Letter of Dedication are in letterpress; the music is engraved.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SONATES POUR Le Violoncelle et Basse Continuë OU Le Violon Seul & Basse. Composées Par ANTONIO FILTZ Mises au jour par Mr DE LA CHEVARDIERE. Prix 4tt. 4s. ŒUVRE V. Gravées par P. L. Charpentier. A PARIS Chez Mr. De La Chevardiere rue du Roule à la Croix d'Or. Et aux Adresses Ordinaires de Musique. Avec Privilege Exclusif, 1779; F797; Score, folio, 277 x approx. 285 (approx. 193 x approx. 202): Title, verso catalogue [Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 82-83, No. I]. Catalogue [Johansson/French, facs. 60], [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Inner and bottom margins of title-page are severely trimmed, with some loss of text on second catalogue.
  Variatione 2/4
  Sonatas, violoncello, continuo, op. 5; Filtz, Johann Anton, 1733-1760; La Chevardière, Louis Balthazard de, 1730-1812; Croix d'Or; Charpentier, P. L. (Pierre Laurent); La Chevardière, Louis Balthazard de, 1730-1812; Paris (France); Variations; A; D; C; 2/4; 3; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Variazione
  Issued with catalogues of the same date. Originally published in 1763, announced in Mercure de France, October, 1763, (Johansson/French, v. 2, p. 68).
- Six TRIOS Concertants Pour Deux Violons et Basse Composés Par M. FIORILLO Œuvre XI. et 2e. Livre de Trios Prix. 9tt. A. PARIS. Chéz le Sr. Sieber Musicien rue St. honoré entre celles des Vielles Etuves et celle D'orléans chez l'Apothicaire No 85 III2, 1791; F894; Three parts, quarto, 251x160 (267x200): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-18. Blank, [19]. Music, pp. 20-21. Blank, [22]. Music, pp. 23-25. Blank, [26]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-18. Blank, [19]. Music, pp. 20-22. Violoncello: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-10. Blank, [11]. Music, pp. 12-15. Blank, [16]. Unfigured. Plate no. III2 throughout. Title-page of VIOLINO PRIMO signed: "Sieber père".
  Rondo poco Vivace 3/8
  TRIO II C
  Allo. assai 2/4
  Rondo Andante 2/4
  Allo. non troppo C
  Rondo Allo. 3/8